

847-528-2326

full resume at:

adamkosecki@gmail.com http://adamkosecki.com/

I am Adam Kosecki, a professional web developer with 10+ years of experience. I create things that are clean; from beautiful, straightforward, comprehensible design elements to robust & readable code.

I strive to understand a problem from all angles before outlining a solution. My solutions are a fair compromise between form and function, fanciness and efficiency, seriousness and fun.

I am a leader. I can make decisions when appropriate, and defer or delegate without shame. People respect me and enjoy working for me.

#### **LANGUAGES**

These are my bread and butter.

JavaScript, PHP, SQL, CSS/LESS, HTML, ColdFusion

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, Programming Emphasis Minor in Psychology

Western Illinois University 2000-2004

### **EXPERIENCE**

## **HelpSystems**

VP of Product 2014 - 2015 / Full-time

2015 - Present / Consultant

Currently evangelizing best practices and modern techniques for this startup; breathing new life in to old UIs; and transitioning the product from an on-premise, single-user solution to a multi-tenant, SaaS, cloud application.

# HelpSystems

Senior Developer

2014 - 2015 / Full-time 2015 - Present / Consultant Developed and deployed an HTML5, mobile-first invoicing application in PHP/AngularJS/MySql to facilitate an end-to-end process for online ordering and payments. The application was built around robust API allowing it integrate with multiple, disparate back-end systems.

Provided guidance regarding front end user experience, SEO, and deployment for the company's public web entities.

Implemented massive ETL processes to migrate and synchronize data between HelpSystems and Network Automation servers throughout the acquisition process.

#### **Network Automation**

LEAD DEVELOPER
UI DESIGN (WEB & WINDOWS APP)

MS SQL DBA

2005 - 2014

Created entire public web entity for company, including all visual design elements, technological decisions (language/framework/server), coding, SEO decisions, optimization for user experience & retention, and... everything else:

Lead onborading / Customer online account / Marketing content / Product downloads / Shopping cart system / License issuing / Support ticketing system / Customer Resource Center / Channel Partner Portal / CMS to manage marketing and support content.

Served as company DBA, implementing best practices including full normalization of existing MS SQL database.

Inherited, managed, enhanced, and enriched existing (homegrown) corporate CRM.tv